[
    { "question" : "ser", "answer" : "to be", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɛɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "ter", "answer" : "to have", "pronunciation" : "ˈtɛɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "estar", "answer" : "to be", "pronunciation" : "iʃˈtaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "fazer", "answer" : "to do", "pronunciation" : "fɐˈzeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dizer", "answer" : "to say", "pronunciation" : "diˈzeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "ir", "answer" : "to go", "pronunciation" : "iɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "ver", "answer" : "to see", "pronunciation" : "ˈvɛɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "poder", "answer" : "to be able", "pronunciation" : "poˈdeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "querer", "answer" : "to want", "pronunciation" : "keˈɾeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "chegar", "answer" : "to arrive", "pronunciation" : "ʃeˈɡaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "saber", "answer" : "to know", "pronunciation" : "sɐˈbeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "dar", "answer" : "to give", "pronunciation" : "ˈdaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "parecer", "answer" : "to seem", "pronunciation" : "pɐɾeˈseɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "sair", "answer" : "to go out", "pronunciation" : "ˈsajɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "sentir", "answer" : "to feel", "pronunciation" : "sẽˈtiɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "ficar", "answer" : "to stay", "pronunciation" : "fiˈkaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "achar", "answer" : "to think", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈʃaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "vir", "answer" : "to come", "pronunciation" : "viɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "precisar", "answer" : "to need", "pronunciation" : "pɾɨziˈzaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "deixar", "answer" : "to let", "pronunciation" : "deiˈʃaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "continuar", "answer" : "to continue", "pronunciation" : "kõtiˈnu.aɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "olhar", "answer" : "to look", "pronunciation" : "oˈʎaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "ouvir", "answer" : "to hear", "pronunciation" : "oˈviɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "pensar", "answer" : "to think", "pronunciation" : "pẽnˈsaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "pedir", "answer" : "to ask", "pronunciation" : "peˈdiɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "começar", "answer" : "to start", "pronunciation" : "kõseˈsaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "encontrar", "answer" : "to find", "pronunciation" : "ẽkõtɾɐr", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "trazer", "answer" : "to bring", "pronunciation" : "tɾaˈzeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "entender", "answer" : "to understand", "pronunciation" : "ẽtẽnˈdeɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "passar", "answer" : "to pass", "pronunciation" : "pɐˈsaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "precisar de", "answer" : "to need", "pronunciation" : "pɾɨziˈzaɾ dʒi", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "trabalhar", "answer" : "to work", "pronunciation" : "tɾɐbɐˈʎaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "falar", "answer" : "to speak", "pronunciation" : "faˈlaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "tomar", "answer" : "to take", "pronunciation" : "toˈmaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "sentir-se", "answer" : "to feel", "pronunciation" : "sẽˈtiɾ sɨ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "voltar", "answer" : "to return", "pronunciation" : "voɫˈtaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "devolver", "answer" : "to return", "pronunciation" : "dɨvoɫˈveɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "mudar", "answer" : "to change", "pronunciation" : "muˈdaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "acabar", "answer" : "to end", "pronunciation" : "ɐkɐˈbaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "conhecer", "answer" : "to know", "pronunciation" : "kõˈnɛseɾ", "part_of_speech" : "verb" },
    { "question" : "tempo", "answer" : "time", "pronunciation" : "ˈtɛmpu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "vida", "answer" : "life", "pronunciation" : "ˈvidɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "dia", "answer" : "day", "pronunciation" : "ˈdi.ɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "ano", "answer" : "year", "pronunciation" : "ˈɐnu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "coisa", "answer" : "thing", "pronunciation" : "ˈkozɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "casa", "answer" : "house", "pronunciation" : "ˈkazɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pessoa", "answer" : "person", "pronunciation" : "pɨˈso.ɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mundo", "answer" : "world", "pronunciation" : "ˈmũdu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "trabalho", "answer" : "work", "pronunciation" : "tɾɐˈbaʎu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "momento", "answer" : "moment", "pronunciation" : "moˈmẽtu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "amor", "answer" : "love", "pronunciation" : "aˈmoɾ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "parte", "answer" : "part", "pronunciation" : "ˈpaɾtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "forma", "answer" : "form", "pronunciation" : "ˈfoɾmɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "lugar", "answer" : "place", "pronunciation" : "luˈɡaɾ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "razão", "answer" : "reason", "pronunciation" : "ʁɐˈzɐ̃w̃", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "vez", "answer" : "time", "pronunciation" : "ˈvɛz", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "país", "answer" : "country", "pronunciation" : "paˈiʃ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "família", "answer" : "family", "pronunciation" : "fɐˈmiʎiɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "noite", "answer" : "night", "pronunciation" : "ˈnojtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "caso", "answer" : "case", "pronunciation" : "ˈkazu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "sentido", "answer" : "sense", "pronunciation" : "sẽˈtʃidu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "amor", "answer" : "love", "pronunciation" : "aˈmoɾ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "amigo", "answer" : "friend", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈmiɡu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "verdade", "answer" : "truth", "pronunciation" : "vɨˈdadɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mente", "answer" : "mind", "pronunciation" : "ˈmẽtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "água", "answer" : "water", "pronunciation" : "ˈaɡwɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "momento", "answer" : "moment", "pronunciation" : "moˈmẽtu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "trabalho", "answer" : "work", "pronunciation" : "tɾɐˈbaʎu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "semana", "answer" : "week", "pronunciation" : "siˈmɐ̃nɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "idade", "answer" : "age", "pronunciation" : "iˈdadɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "sol", "answer" : "sun", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɔw̃", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "rua", "answer" : "street", "pronunciation" : "ˈʁu.ɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "criança", "answer" : "child", "pronunciation" : "kɾiˈɐ̃sɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "problema", "answer" : "problem", "pronunciation" : "pɾuˈblɛmɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "escola", "answer" : "school", "pronunciation" : "iʃˈkoɫɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "trabalho", "answer" : "work", "pronunciation" : "tɾɐˈbaʎu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "amor", "answer" : "love", "pronunciation" : "aˈmoɾ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "livro", "answer" : "book", "pronunciation" : "ˈlivɾu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "sentido", "answer" : "sense", "pronunciation" : "sẽˈtʃidu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "corpo", "answer" : "body", "pronunciation" : "ˈkoɾpu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mundo", "answer" : "world", "pronunciation" : "ˈmũdu", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "pai", "answer" : "father", "pronunciation" : "ˈpaj", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "mãe", "answer" : "mother", "pronunciation" : "ˈmɐ̃j", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "hora", "answer" : "hour", "pronunciation" : "ˈoɾɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "cabeça", "answer" : "head", "pronunciation" : "kaˈbe.sɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "palavra", "answer" : "word", "pronunciation" : "paˈɾavɾɐ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "cidade", "answer" : "city", "pronunciation" : "siˈdadɨ", "part_of_speech" : "noun" },
    { "question" : "bom", "answer" : "good", "pronunciation" : "bõm", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "grande", "answer" : "big", "pronunciation" : "ˈɡɾãdɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "novo", "answer" : "new", "pronunciation" : "ˈnovu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "velho", "answer" : "old", "pronunciation" : "ˈvɛʎu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "importante", "answer" : "important", "pronunciation" : "ĩpoɾˈtɐ̃tɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "certo", "answer" : "certain", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɛɾtu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "difícil", "answer" : "difficult", "pronunciation" : "ˈdifisɨw̃", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "diferente", "answer" : "different", "pronunciation" : "difɨˈɾẽtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "pequeno", "answer" : "small", "pronunciation" : "pɨˈkenu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "próximo", "answer" : "next", "pronunciation" : "ˈpɾɔksimu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "feliz", "answer" : "happy", "pronunciation" : "ˈfɛlis", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "mesmo", "answer" : "same", "pronunciation" : "ˈmeʃmu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "público", "answer" : "public", "pronunciation" : "ˈpubliku", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "possível", "answer" : "possible", "pronunciation" : "poˈsivɛw̃", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "social", "answer" : "social", "pronunciation" : "suˈsjaɫ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "alto", "answer" : "tall", "pronunciation" : "ˈawtu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "forte", "answer" : "strong", "pronunciation" : "ˈfɔɾtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "real", "answer" : "real", "pronunciation" : "ʁɨˈaɫ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "próprio", "answer" : "proper", "pronunciation" : "ˈpɾɔpɾju", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "antigo", "answer" : "old", "pronunciation" : "ɐ̃ˈtiɡu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "branco", "answer" : "white", "pronunciation" : "ˈbɾɐ̃ku", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "preto", "answer" : "black", "pronunciation" : "ˈpɾetu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "único", "answer" : "unique", "pronunciation" : "ˈuniku", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "jovem", "answer" : "young", "pronunciation" : "ʒoˈvẽ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "especial", "answer" : "special", "pronunciation" : "ispeˈsjaw", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "forte", "answer" : "strong", "pronunciation" : "ˈfɔɾtɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "belo", "answer" : "beautiful", "pronunciation" : "ˈbɛlu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "enorme", "answer" : "enormous", "pronunciation" : "ẽˈɾɔmi", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "fácil", "answer" : "easy", "pronunciation" : "ˈfasɨw̃", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "último", "answer" : "last", "pronunciation" : "ˈuɫtimu", "part_of_speech" : "adjective" },
    { "question" : "aqui", "answer" : "here", "pronunciation" : "aˈki", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "agora", "answer" : "now", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈɡɔɾɐ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "já", "answer" : "already", "pronunciation" : "ʒa", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "também", "answer" : "also", "pronunciation" : "tɐ̃ˈbẽj", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "só", "answer" : "only", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɔ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "sempre", "answer" : "always", "pronunciation" : "ˈsẽpɾi", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "ainda", "answer" : "still", "pronunciation" : "ˈaj̃dɐ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "muito", "answer" : "very", "pronunciation" : "ˈmujtu", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "bem", "answer" : "well", "pronunciation" : "ˈbẽj", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "talvez", "answer" : "maybe", "pronunciation" : "tawˈvɛʃ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "então", "answer" : "then", "pronunciation" : "ẽˈtɐ̃w̃", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "apenas", "answer" : "only", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈpɛnɐs", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "mesmo", "answer" : "even", "pronunciation" : "ˈmeʃmu", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "bastante", "answer" : "quite", "pronunciation" : "bɐˈtɐ̃stɨ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "tão", "answer" : "so", "pronunciation" : "ˈtɐ̃w̃", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "mais", "answer" : "more", "pronunciation" : "ˈmajʃ", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "pouco", "answer" : "a little", "pronunciation" : "ˈpɔku", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "cedo", "answer" : "early", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɛdu", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "lá", "answer" : "there", "pronunciation" : "ˈla", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "assim", "answer" : "like this", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈsim", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "quase", "answer" : "almost", "pronunciation" : "ˈkwazi", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "logo", "answer" : "soon", "pronunciation" : "ˈlɔɡu", "part_of_speech" : "adverb" },
    { "question" : "e", "answer" : "and", "pronunciation" : "ˈi", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "que", "answer" : "that", "pronunciation" : "ˈkɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "ou", "answer" : "or", "pronunciation" : "ˈow", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "mas", "answer" : "but", "pronunciation" : "ˈmaʃ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "se", "answer" : "if", "pronunciation" : "ˈsɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "porque", "answer" : "because", "pronunciation" : "pɔrkˈkɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "embora", "answer" : "although", "pronunciation" : "ẽˈboɾɐ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "como", "answer" : "like", "pronunciation" : "ˈkɔmu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "quando", "answer" : "when", "pronunciation" : "ˈkwɐ̃du", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "enquanto", "answer" : "while", "pronunciation" : "ẽˈkwɐ̃tu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "até", "answer" : "until", "pronunciation" : "ˈatɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "mesmo", "answer" : "even", "pronunciation" : "ˈmeʃmu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "pois", "answer" : "so", "pronunciation" : "ˈpojʃ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "seja", "answer" : "whether", "pronunciation" : "ˈʃɛʒɐ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "contudo", "answer" : "however", "pronunciation" : "kõˈtudu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "ora", "answer" : "now", "pronunciation" : "ˈɔɾɐ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "como se", "answer" : "as if", "pronunciation" : "ˈkɔmusɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "para que", "answer" : "so that", "pronunciation" : "pɐˈɾakɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "depois", "answer" : "after", "pronunciation" : "ˈdɛpojʃ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "antes", "answer" : "before", "pronunciation" : "ˈɐ̃tɨʃ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "desde que", "answer" : "since", "pronunciation" : "ˈdɛsdu kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "visto que", "answer" : "given that", "pronunciation" : "ˈvistu kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "tanto quanto", "answer" : "as much as", "pronunciation" : "ˈtɐ̃tu ˈkwɐ̃tu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "senão", "answer" : "otherwise", "pronunciation" : "sɨˈnɐ̃w̃", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "assim que", "answer" : "as soon as", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈsim kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "conforme", "answer" : "according to", "pronunciation" : "kõˈfɔɾmɨ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "desde", "answer" : "from", "pronunciation" : "ˈdɛsdu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "por isso", "answer" : "therefore", "pronunciation" : "pɔˈɾizw̃", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "se bem que", "answer" : "although", "pronunciation" : "sɛ ˈbẽj kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "tanto que", "answer" : "so much that", "pronunciation" : "ˈtɐ̃tu kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "porém", "answer" : "however", "pronunciation" : "pɔˈɾẽj", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "malgrado", "answer" : "in spite of", "pronunciation" : "mɐɫˈɡɾaðu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "salvo se", "answer" : "unless", "pronunciation" : "ˈsawvu sɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "já que", "answer" : "since", "pronunciation" : "ˈʒa kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "como se não", "answer" : "as if not", "pronunciation" : "ˈkɔmusɛ ˈnɐ̃w̃", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "logo que", "answer" : "as soon as", "pronunciation" : "ˈlɔɡu kɛ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "assim como", "answer" : "as well as", "pronunciation" : "ɐˈsim ˈkɔmu", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" },
    { "question" : "ou seja", "answer" : "in other words", "pronunciation" : "ˈow ˈʃɛʒɐ", "part_of_speech" : "conjunction" }
]